RG 074:034, Lawrence Van Alstyne Notebooks on the Ogden Family
Connecticut State Library
Lawrence Val Alstyne notebooks on the Ogden family
1891-1911
Connecticut State Library
Van Alstyne, Lawrence, 1839-
1.5 cubic feet
Genealogical notes on the Ogden Family collected from various sources in Connecticut, New York and New Jersey.
RG074_034
1942-014
Biographical Note
Lawrence Van Alstyne was born in 1839 and lived in Sharon, Conn. He died on November 30, 1923.
Van Alstyne authored: Born, married and died, in Sharon, Connecticut: a record of births, marriages and deaths, in the town of Sharon, Conn.,from 1721 to 1879. Taken from the ancient land and church records and other authentic sources (1897); Lambert Janse Van Alstyne and some of his descendents (1897); Burying Grounds Of Sharon, Connecticut, Amenia And North East, New York (1903); Diary of an enlisted man (1910); Manufacturing in Sharon (Orig. 1912); Merchants of Sharon: history concerning the merchants of the town of Sharon, Connecticut (Orig. 1915) and co-edited Ogden family in America: Elizabethtown branch and their English ancestry: John Ogden, the Pilgrim, and his descendants, 1640-1906; their history, biography & genealogy (1907).
Scope and Content
Genealogical notes on the Ogden Family collected from various sources in Connecticut, New York and New Jersey. Included are three indexes: Births and deaths; Marriages; Mentions in notebooks 1 to 25.
Related Material
Ogden family: History and Genealogy Unit Special Genealogical File, 1949-circa 1999
Index Terms
Persons:
Van Alstyne, Lawrence, 1839-
Family Names:
Ogden family
Places:
Connecticut -- Genealogy; New Jersey -- Genealogy; New York -- Genealogy
Document Types:
Notebooks
Restrictions on Access
These records are stored at an off-site facility and therefore may not be available on a same-day basis.
See the policy.
Container List
- Notebooks, 1891-1911
  - Number 2, 1891 October 10 - 1891 October 20 (Box 1)
  - Number 5, 1891 December 16 - 1892 May 3 (Box 1)
  - Numbers 6-7, 1892 January 30 - July 17 (Box 1)
  - Number 8, 1892 August 1 - December 2 (Box 1)
  - Number 9, 1892 October 26 - 1983 July (Box 1)
  - Number 9 1/2, 1892 October 10 (Box 1)
  - Number 10, 1893 February 2 - 1894 February 1 (Box 1)
  - Number 11, 1893 March 3 - 1894 April 2 (Box 1)
  - Number 12, 1893 July 6 - 1894 July 25 (Box 1)
  - Notes from L.V.A.'s note books 1 to 30 copied by R.E.G., 1898 (Box 1)
  - Number 13, 1893 July 17 - 1894 March 29 (Box 2)
  - Number 14, 1893 December 12 - 1899 June 9 (Box 2)
  - Number 15, 1894 May 7 - June 12 (Box 2)
  - Number 16, 1894 February 7 - 29 (Box 2)
  - Number 17, 1894 March 2 - 17 (Box 2)
  - Number 18, 1895 November 20 - 1896 January 31 (Box 2)
  - Number 19, 1896 February 6 - 13 (Box 2)
  - Number 20, 1896 February 25-27 (Box 2)
  - Number 21, 1893 September 26 - 1894 February 10 (Box 2)
  - Number 22, 1893 November 21 - 28 (Box 2)
  - Number 23, 1895 (Box 2)
  - Number 24, undated (Box 2)
  - Number 25, 1895 April 9 - 1896 May 29 (Box 2)
  - Number 26, 1895 April 14 - 1900 September 20 (Box 2)
  - Number 27, 1896 September 16 - 1911 June 26 (Box 2)
  - Number 29, 1896 September 16 - 1897 September 22 (Box 2)
  - Number 30, 1898 January 7 - May 20 (Box 2)
  - Indexes (Box 3)
    - Births and deaths (Box 3)
    - Marriages (Box 3)
    - Mentions in notebooks 1 to 25 (Box 3)